Permanent Address:

709, Sarthi Height,
Nr. Kanba Hospital,
Nikol, Ahmedabad – 382350,
Gujarat, India.
Mobile - +91 96248 35180
Email – panchaljainil8@gmail.com

Jainil Panchal

Driven professional with broad technical skills, strong attention to detail and 4+ years' experience in front-end development. Able to work in agile methodology. On top of the latest trends and technologies. Ability to improvise troubleshoots, take ownership, and learn new skills on the job.

Technical Highlights

Web Skills: HTML {Handlebars}, CSS {SASS}, JavaScript {ES6 & Web Component} & Frameworks {jQuery, React}, XML, JSON, CMS integration, NextJS/MERN {Beginner}, Sitecore, Wordpress, web standards and accessibility {W3C, ADA}, cross-browser compatibility, mobile web design.

Web Tools: MS Visual Studio Code, Figma, Slack, Gulp, FTP clients, Subversion (Git), JIRA.

Debugging Tools: Chrome Developer Tool, IE Developer Tool.

Content Management Systems: SiteCore, WordPress.

Operating Systems: Microsoft Windows, Linux and Mac.

Professional Experience

Investis Digital (IDX). (https://www.investisdigital.com/)

Frontend Developer

April 2023 - Present

Spearheaded the development of dynamic and responsive web applications using Sitecore, resulting in a 30% improvement in user engagement. Collaborated with UX/UI designers to create visually appealing and intuitive interfaces, ensuring a positive user experience. Implemented RESTful APIs for seamless data communication and integration with backend services. Coded using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.

Atlas Softweb Pvt. Ltd. (https://www.atlassoftweb.com/)

Frontend Developer

September 2022 - March 2023

Developed and maintained websites on wordpress and ReactJS, implementing custom themes and plugins to meet client specifications. Utilized Sass and Less preprocessors to optimize CSS development, improving code maintainability and readability. Integrated jQuery to enhance interactivity and responsiveness, resulting in a more engaging user experience.

Veb-builders Technology. (https://vebbuilders.com/)

Frontend Developer

August 2021 - September 2022

Played a key role in building modern and scalable web applications using ReactJS and JavaScript. Collaborated with the backend team to integrate frontend components with Firebase ensuring efficient data retrieval and manipulation. Utilized Git for version control and actively participated in Agile development sprints.

Sprig-stack. (https://sprigstack.com/)

Junior. Frontend Developer

October 2019 - April 2021

Gained foundational experience in frontend development, focusing on HTML, CSS, and JavaScript{jQuery}. Assisted in the implementation of UI features using jQuery, contributing to improved website functionality.Participated in code reviews and collaborated with the team to troubleshoot and resolve issues.

Strengths

Give more importance to quality.

Ability to work in a Team Oriented environment.

Ability to work creatively even with the simplest designs.

Capacity of time management in my work.

Education

BCA - 2018-2021 from Shri Chimanbhai Patel Institute of Computer Applications, Gujarat University.

Personal Detail

Date of Birth: October 08, 2000

Websites:

Logistics Real Estate in Europe - https://www.logicor.eu/en

Mclaren Investor Site - https://investors.mclaren.com/

Prosus - https://www.prosus.com/

Rolls-Royce Investor - https://www.rolls-royce.com/investors.aspx (Maintenance)

ReactJS based:

Home Watch - https://myhomewatch-admin.web.app/

Energie Fitness – https://energie-fitness-1db27.web.app/

Gotu Shop - https://gotushop.in/